Guide to the Andover Newton Faculty Publications Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Individuals A-L, Series I
  - Burton, Ernest DeWitt
    - "Ministerial Education: Possible Reforms in Our Method of Aiding Young Men Preparing for the Ministry." A paper read before the Northern Baptist Education Society at its annual meeting in Pittsfield, Mass, October 28, 1890. (Box 9)
    - "Papers on the Newton Theological Institution" The Watchman Extra (January 15, 1891) [includes the 1890 article above] (Box 9)
    - Syntax of the Moods and Tenses in New Testament Greek. Chicago: University Press of Chicago, 1893. (Box 9)
    - "The Function of Interpretation in Relation to Theology" American Journal of Theology 2, no. 1 (January 1898): 52-79. (Box 9)
    - Notes on New Testament Grammar. Revised Edition. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1904. (Box 9)
    - "What Should the Churches Demand of the Theological Schools?" The Biblical World 25 no. 1 (January 1905): 20-29. (Box 9)
    - An Open Letter to a Christian Young Man in College. Second Edition. [no publisher information], no date (Box 9)
  - Carlston, Charles
    - Parables of the Triple Tradition. Philadelphia: Fortress Press, 1975. (Box 10)
    - Epiphany: Series B (Proclamation 3). Philadelphia: Fortress Press, 1984. (Box 10)
    - "The Canon—Problems and Benefits." The Bulletin of [the] Christian Research Institute Meiji Gakuin University no.73 (1990) [reprint from, so page numbers do not match]. (Box 10)
    - "Christology and Church in Matthew." In The Four Gospels: Festschrift Frans Neirynck. Ed. F. Van Segbroeck et al., 1283-1304. Leuven: University Press, 1992. (Box 10)
  - Chase, Irah
    - The Sentence of Our Lord on Anger. Washington City: Printed by Anderson and Meehan, 1822. (Box 11)
    - Remarks on the Book of Daniel .... Boston: Gould, Kendall, and Lincoln, 1844. (Box 11)
    - "Rev. Irah Chase, D. D.: An Autobiographical Sketch." In The Baptist Memorial and Monthly Record, Devoted to the History, Biography, Literature and Statistics of the Denomination v.9, n.s.v.2 New York: Z.P. Hatch, 1850, 70–82. (Box 11)
    - The Design of Baptism, Viewed in its Relation to the Christian Life. Boston: Gould and Lincoln, 1851. (Box 11)
    - Bunsen's View of Baptism, Ancient and Modern. Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society, 1853. (Box 11)
    - Infant Baptism, an Invention of Men; or Dr. Bushnell's Arguments Reviewed. Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society, 1863. (Box 11)
  - Clark, Walter Houston
    - "Religion as a Response to the Search for Meaning: Its Relation to Skepticism and Creativity." The Journal of Social Psychology 60 (1963): 127-37. (Box 5)
    - W.H.C. and Timothy Leary. "Religious Implication of Consciousness Expanding Drugs." Religious Education (May-June 1963): 251-56. (Box 5)
    - "William James: Contributions to the Psychology of Religious Conversion." Pastoral Psychology (September 1965) [no pagination] (Box 5)
    - "The Psychology of Religious Experience." Psychology Today (February 1968): 42-47. (Box 5)
    - "The Mystical Consciousness and Contribution to Human Understanding." Humanitas Journal of the Institute of Man. VI3 (Winter 1971): 311-324. (Box 5)
  - Clouse, William Jacob
    - A Teacher's Message: A Memorial of Hannah Perkins Dodge, 1821–1896. Boston: Alfred Mudge & Son, 1896. (Box 12)
  - Costas, Orlando Enrique
    - Comunicacion Por Medio De La Predicacion: Manual De Homiletica. San Jose and Miami: Editorial Caribe, 1982. (Box 13)
    - Predicacion Evangelica y Teologia Hispana. ed. OC. San Diego, CA: Publicaciones de las Americas, 1982. (Box 13)
    - "La vida en el espiritu." Boletin Teologico Revista de las Fraternidad Teologica Latinoamerica 18 (June 1986): 7–25. (Box 13)
    - "Forward In Partnership." Unpublished address given at the American Baptist Churches June 1987 biennial, Pittsburgh, PA.
  - Copenhaver, Martin B.
    - Jesus is the Question: The 307 Questions Jesus Asked And The 3 He Answered. Nashville: Abingdon Press, 2014. (Box 5)
    - Room to Grow: Meditations on Trying to Live as a Christian. Grand Rapids: Wm. B. Eerdmans Publishing Co., 2015. (Box 5)
  - Cragg, Gerald R.
    - "Disunities created by differing patterns of church life." In SOCIAL AND CULTURAL FACTORS IN CHURCH DIVISIONS, 12-18. New York: World Council of Churches, 1952. (Box 14)
    - Predication sur I Pierre 1:3-9. (Unpublished address given 08/16/1954) (Box 14)
    - A IGREJA E A IDADE DA RAZAO. Lisbon: Editora Ulisseia, 1960. (Box 14)
    - "Ordination." HARVARD DIVINITY BULLETIN 24 (April 1960): 20-29. (Box 15)
    - THE CHURCH AND THE AGE OF REASON, 1648-1789. New York: Atheneum, 1961. (Box 14)
    - REASON AND AUTHORITY IN THE EIGHTEENTH CENTURY. London: Cambridge University Press, 1964. (Box 15)
    - THE CHURCH AND THE WORLD. Toronto: United Church Publishing House, 1966. (Box 14)
    - "The collapse of militant Puritanism." In ESSAYS IN MODERN ENGLISH CHURCH HISTORY. ed. G.V. Bennett and J.D. Walsh, 76-103. London: Black, 1966. (Box 14)
    - THE CAMBRIDGE PLATONISTS. ed. by GRC. New York: Oxford University Press, 1968. (Box 15)
    - "The European wellsprings of Canadian Christianity." THEOLOGICAL BULLETIN 3 (January 1968): 4-13. (Box 14)
    - THE WORKS OF JOHN WESLEY, v.2: THE APPEALS TO MEN OF REASON AND RELIGION AND CERTAIN RELATED OPEN LETTERS. ed. by GRC. Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1975. (Box 14)
    - "On loving God with our whole minds." ANDOVER NEWTON QUARTERLY n.s.v. 16 (January 1976): 207-209. (Box 14)
  - Dabney, Vaughan
    - "Changing Emphases In Theological Education." [no publication information given: possibly an address given at the 143d Annual Meeting of the Rhode Island Baptist Education Society]. [no date]. (Box 5)
  - de Blois, Austen Kennedy
    - Fighters for Freedom. Philadelphia: Judson Press, 1929. (Box 16)
  - Drummond, Sarah Birmingham
    - Holy Clarity: The Practice of Planning and Evaluation. Herndon, VA: The Alban Institute, 2009. (Box 5)
    - Leading Change In Campus Religious Life: A Case Study on the Programs for the Theological Exploration of Vocation. Saarbrücken, Deutschland/Germany: Scholar's Press, 2015. (Box 5)
  - Dunstan, John Leslie
    - "Writings of faith and encouragement: International uniform lessons for the summer quarter." Pilgrim Uniform Quarterly 6 (July-September 1956): 9-64. "Verse by verse" sections only. (Box 17)
    - "The interdependence of men and the role of religions." Civilizations 7/4 (1957): 489-499. (Box 17)
    - "Writings of faith and encouragement: International uniform lessons for the summer quarter." Pilgrim Uniform Quarterly 6 (July-September 1956): 9-64. "Verse by verse" sections only. (Box 17)
    - "The mission of Jesus." Pilgrim Uniform Quarterly 9 (October-December 1958): 3-5. (Box 17)
    - "The ever-present cross." Pilgrim Uniform Quarterly 9 (January-March 1959): 7-9., 159
    - "Living as witnesses." Pilgrim Uniform Quarterly 10 (October-December 1959): 3-5. (Box 17)
    - "The mission of the church today." Pilgrim Uniform Quarterly 10 (January-March 1960): 6-8. (Box 17)
    - Protestantism. New York: Braziller, 1961. (Box 17)
    - Jesus the Christ. Boston: United Church Press, 1963. (Box 17)
    - A light to the city; 150 years of the City Mission Society of Boston, 1816-1966. Boston: Beacon Press, 1966. (Box 17)
  - Edwards, Bela Bates
    - Memoir of the Rev. Elias Cornelius. Boston: Perkins & Marvin, 1833. (Box 18)
    - Writings of Prof. B.B. Edwards, with a Memoir by Edwards A. Park. 2 vols. Boston: John P. Jewett, 1853. (Box 18)
  - Emerson, Ralph
    - "On Provoking Our Children to Wrath." The Mother's Magazine and Family Library 11/8 (August 1843): 183-189 and 11/9 (September 1843): 193-202. (Box 19)
    - A Sermon Delivered at Hollis, N.H. at the Funeral of Rev. Eli Smith, on Friday, May 14, 1847. Andover: William H. Wardwell, 1847. (Box 19)
  - English, John Mahan
    - "The Truth as it is in the Minster" The Watchman (June 30, 1910): 9-10. (Box 19)
    - For Pulpit and Platform. New York: The Macmillan Co., 1919. (Box 19)
    - The Pastor's Preparation for Evangelism: An Address Delivered at the New England Conference on Evangelism Held in Tremont Temple, Boston, September 9-12, 1923, Under the Auspices of the Department of Evangelism. New York: The American Baptist Home Mission Society. (Box 19)
    - The Minister and His Ministry. Philadelphia: Judson Press, 1924. (Box 19)
  - Evans, Daniel
    - "American and European Christianity." The Congregationalist 108/25 (21 June 1923): 785. (Box 19)
    - "The Meaning and Value of a Liberal Education." The University Record 13 (October 1927): 289-301. (Box 19)
    - "Through All to God." The Journal of Religion 10/1 (January 1930): 22-36. (Box 19)
    - "The Ethics of Jesus and the Modern Mind." (Address at opening of academic year at Andover Theological Seminary and Harvard Divinity School, September 29, 1911) (Box 19)
    - "The Divine Revelation and the Christian Religion." (Dudleian Lecture, delivered at Harvard University, May 2, 1912) (Box 19)
    - "Humanism: A Discussion by Prof. Auer and Prof. Evans." Institution Bulletin 26 (March 1934): 3-14. (Box 19)
    - "George A. Gordon: Preacher-Theologian." (The Southworth Lectures, 1939). (Box 19)
  - Everett, William J.
    - "Persons in Drama, Law and Theology." Perspectives (Harvard Divinity School) 2 (Fall 1968): 8-27. (Box 20)
    - "The Churches and Radical Social Change in the USA." In The Encounter of the Churches with Movements of Social Change in Various Cultural Contexts, part I, 105-116. Geneva: Lutheran World Federation, 1977. (Box 20)
    - "Theology and the Behavioral Sciences: An Approach to Critical Methodology." In The Encounter of the Churches with Movements of Social Change in Various Cultural Contexts, part II, 165-174. Geneva: Lutheran World Federation, 1977. (Box 20)
    - "Religion and Federalism: Some Comparative Hypotheses." The Quest for Self-determination and Democracy in the Horn of Africa: The Case of Oromia, 21-31. Washington, D.C.: Oromo Studies Association Proceedings., 1995 (Box 20)
    - Religion, Federalism, and the Struggle for Public Life: Cases from Germany, India and America. New York: Oxford University Press, 1997. (Box 20)
    - The Politics of Worship: Reforming the Language and Symbols of Liturgy. Cleveland, OH: United Church Press, 1999. (Box 20)
  - Fackre, Gabriel
    - "Review of Nihilism by Helmut Thielicke, translated by John W. Doberstein." Theology and Life 4:3 (1961): 252-253. (Box 21)
    - "The New Breed." [Unpublished sermon preached in Schwab Auditorium, January 12, 1964.] (Box 21)
    - "Review of Theological Ethics by James Sellers." Religion in Life 35:5 (Autumn 1966):181-183. (Box 21)
    - "The Crisis of the Congregation: A Debate," Voluntary Associations: Essays in Honor of James Luther Adams, D. B. Robertson, editor. John Knox Press, 1966. (Box 21)
    - What Happens in Baptism?, Living Faith Series, Westminster Press, 1967. (Box 21)
    - "Review of The Pastor and the Race Issue by Daisuke Kitagawa." Review of Religious Research 8:2 (Winter 1967): 119-120. (Box 21)
    - "Review of Richard E. Moore and Duane L. Day, Urban Church Breakthrough" ." Publication unidentified (Winter 1967). (Box 21)
    - "Some Reflections on the Church for Others: (with particular reference to the report of the North American group)." Concept (November 1968): 12-17. (Box 21)
    - "Redesigning life: scenarios and guidelines." In Should Doctors Play God, ed. Claudia Frazier, 1-8. Nashville: Broadman Press, 1971. (mimeographed format) (Box 21)
    - Memory and Hope in a Time of Nostalgia, Council for Lay Life and Work, UCC 1972. (Box 21)
    - "Outside-In, Inside-Out." In Action: Planning for Evangelism, 27-29. New York: United Church Board of Homeland Ministries, 1973. (Box 21)
    - "Guide to Do and Tell." In New Life Missions Handbook, ed. Board of Discipleship for the United Methodist Church. Nashville: Tidings, 1974. (Box 21)
    - "An Acts theology of evangelism." Religion in Life 44 (Spring 1975): 73-89. (Box 21)
    - "The Supper and our identity." [unpublished address delivered in Chicago, Fall 1978.] (Box 21)
    - "The struggle for unity." In Festival of the Church, 23-34. New York: Office of Church Life and Leadership UCC, 1978. (Box 21)
    - Gabriel Fackre, "A Full-Orbed Gospel," Theological Students Fellowship Bulletin 5.4 (March-April 1982): 17. (Box 21)
    - "Dawn People." In resource book for World Council of Churches, Vancouver, BC, 1983. (Box 21)
    - "The confessional nature of the United Church of Christ." Unpublished manuscript for EKU-UCC seminary dialogue., 1983 (Box 21)
    - "The confessional nature of the United Church of Christ." EKU-UCC Newsletter 5 (February 1984): 2-15. [also in New Conversations (Winter-Spring 1988)] (Box 21)
    - "The Song of a Craigville Swan." [President's report] Annual Report, Christian Camp Meeting Association (July 11, 1987): 1-4. (Box 21)
    - "Perspectives on the Covenants of Israel and Christ." New Conversations 12/3 (Summer 1990): 35-43. (Box 21)
    - "The Reformed-Lutheran Conversation." Craigville VII Theological Colloquy, July 16-20, 1990, 52-56. (Box 21)
    - "Study guide to United Church of Christ: an Ecclesiology." [no additional bibliographic information], 1991 (Box 21)
    - "The state of Systematics: research and commentary." Dialog 31/1 (Winter 1992): 54-61. (Box 21)
    - "Theological Standards in the UCC." Craigville X Theological Colloquy (July 19-23, 1993): 20-26. (Box 21)
    - "Common calling and confessing Christ." (paper at Center for Catholic and Evangelical Theology Conference, St. Olaf College, 1995. (Box 21)
    - "Report to the ELCA Bishops on 'Our Common Calling'." (ELCA Bishop's Conference, Philadelphia, 1996) (Box 21)
    - Article in Japanese, 1996 (Box 21)
    - "The Joint Declaration and the Reformed tradition." (address at Yale Divinity School convocation, 1998) (Box 21)
    - "Bible, community and spirit." Horizons in Biblical Theology 21 (1999): 66-81. (Box 21)
    - "Tradition and traditionalism." Life Together: Under the Word (A Confessing Christ Occasional Paper) 2/1 (Winter 1999-2000): 1-9. (Box 21)
    - "The ecumenical import of the Joint Declaration on the Doctrine of Justification." (paper at American Theological Society, Princeton, 2001). (Box 21)
    - "Christ and Salvation: Dominus Iesus discussed." (paper at "One Path to God" consultation at Andover Newton, 2001). (Box 21)
    - "Issues in Mainline reaction [to September 11]." (unpublished), 2001 (Box 21)
    - "On binding up wounds and resisting powers." September Eleven section of UCC website, dated October 5, 2001. [also published in United Church News] (Box 21)
    - "Being gracious to other religions." Cape Cod Times, December 27, 2001. (Box 21)
    - "Thunderbolt of God." Report from the Center for Catholic and Evangelical Theology, Autumn 2003, 2-6. (Box 21)
    - Theology and Culture Newsletter (Advent 2016). (Box 21)
    - Theology and Culture Newsletter (Advent 2017). (Box 21)
    - "Elements of a Theology of Institutions." Andover Newton Laits[stet] Project Paper, no date. (Box 21)
    - "Propositions on the Ministry: Methodology." Lancoste Seminary Faculty Discussion, no date. (Box 21)
    - Under the Steeple, Abingdon Press, 1957, co-author with Dorothy Fackre (Box 22)
    - The Purpose and Work of the Ministry, Christian Education Press, 1959. (Box 22)
    - The Baptismal Encounter, Lancaster Seminary Occasional Papers, 1962. (Box 22)
    - The Pastor and the World, United Church Press, 1964. (Box 22)
    - Second Fronts in Metropolitan Mission, Eerdmans, 1968. (Box 22)
    - Conversation in Faith, UCC Adult Resource Book, United Church Press, 1968. (Box 22)
    - Secular Impact, Pilgrim Press, 1968. (Box 22)
    - The Rainbow Sign: Christian Futurity, Eerdmans, U.S.A. and Epworth, Great Britain, 1969. (Box 22)
    - Humiliation and Celebration: Post-radical Themes in Doctrine Morals and Mission, Sheed and Ward, 1969. (Box 22)
    - The Promise of Reinhold Niebuhr, Lippincott, 1970. (Box 22)
    - Liberation in Middle America, Pilgrim, 1971. (Box 23)
    - Do and Tell: Engagement Evangelism in the 70s, Eerdmans, 1973. (Box 23)
    - Word In Deed: Theological Themes in Evangelism, Eerdmans, 1975. (Box 23)
    - The Christian Story: A Narrative Interpretation of Basic Christian Doctrine, Eerdmans, 1978. (Box 23)
    - Youth Ministry: The Gospel and the People, (co-author with Jan Chartier), Judson, 1979, 1980. (Box 23)
    - The Religious Right and Christian Faith, Eerdmans, 1982. (Box 23)
    - The Christian Story, Volume 1, revised edition, Eerdmans, 1984. (Box 23)
    - The Christian Story, Volume 2, Authority: Scripture in the Church for the World, Eerdmans, 1987. (Box 23)
    - Christian Basics: A Primer for Pilgrims, co-author with Dorothy Fackre, Eerdmans, 1991-1994, 1998, 2000(6th printing). (Box 23)
    - Sound Doctrine in the Church. The Second Annual Theodore Louis Trost, Jr. Memorial Lecture, October 18, 1992, St. Paul, MN. (Box 23)
    - Ecumenical Faith in Evangelical Perspective, Eerdmans, 1993. (Box 25)
    - The Promise of Reinhold Niebuhr, revised edition, University Press of America, 1994. (Box 24)
    - What About Those Who Have Never Heard?, co-author with Ronald Nash and John Sanders, InterVarsity, 1995. (Box 24)
    - The Christian Story, Vol.1, revised, third edition, Eerdmans, 1996. (Box 25)
    - "What Lutherans and Reformed can learn from each other." On the Way: occasional papers of the Wisconsin Conference of the United Church of Christ 14/1 (Summer 1997): 5-15. (Box 23)
    - The Doctrine of Revelation: A Narrative Interpretation, University of Edinburgh Press, GB and Eerdmans, USA, 1997. (Box 25)
    - Restoring the Center: Essays Evangelical and Ecumenical, InterVarsity, 1998. *Affirmations and Admonitions: Lutheran Decisions and Dialogue, co-author with Michael Root, Eerdmans, 1998. (Box 25)
    - The Day After: A Retrospective on Religious Dissent in the Presidential Crisis, Eerdmans, 2000. (Box 24)
    - Story Lines: Chapters in Thought, Word, and Deed: Festschrift for Gabriel Fackre, Skye F. Gibson, editor, Eerdmans, 2002. (Box 24)
    - Believing, Caring and Doing in the United Church of Christ, Pilgrim Press, 2005. (Box 24)
    - The Christian Story, Vol. 4, Christology in Context, Eerdmans, forthcoming, 2006. (Box 24)
    - The Christian Story, Vol. 5, The Church: Signs of the Spirit and Signs of the Times, Eerdmans, 2007. (Box 24)
  - Fallaw, Wesner
    - "The Group as an Aid in Personnel Guidance." [publication unclear; perhaps North Carolina Education ] (February 1940): 205-213., 1943 (Box 25)
    - "Atomic apocalypse." The Christian Century 60 (July 21, 1943): 844-845. (Box 25)
    - The Modern Parent and the Teaching Church. New York: The Macmillan Company, 1946. (Box 25)
    - "Some theological foundations for Christian education." The Journal of Religion 30 (July 1950): 201-213. (Box 25)
    - "The function of groups in learning Christianity." Religious Education 45 (November-December 1950): 323-330. (Box 25)
    - Toward Spiritual Security. Philadelphia: Westminster Press, 1952. (Box 25)
    - "Religious education in the seminary curriculum." Religious Education 50 (March-April 1955): 122-126. (Box 25)
    - Church Education for Tomorrow. Philadelphia: Westminster Press, 1960. (Box 25)
    - The Case Method in Pastoral and Lay Education. Philadelphia: Westminster Press, 1963. (Box 25)
    - "Governance of the theological school." Theological Education 7 (Autumn 1970): 38-46. (Box 25)
  - Ferré, Nels Frederick Solomon
    - Swedish Contributions to Modern Theology. New York: Harper, 1939. (Box 26)
    - The Christian Fellowship. New York: Harper, 1940. (Box 26)
    - The Christian Faith: An Inquiry into its Adequacy as Man's Ultimate Religion. New York: Harper, 1942. (Box 26)
    - Doctrina Christiana del Hombre. New York: Comité de Literatura Christiana, 1943. (Box 26)
    - Return to Christianity. New York: Harper, 1943. (Box 26)
    - Faith and Reason. New York: Harper, 1946. (Box 27)
    - Evil and the Christian Faith. New York: Harper, 1947. (Box 27)
    - Pillars of Faith. New York: Harper, 1948. (Box 27)
    - Christianity and Society. New York: Harper, 1950. (Box 27)
    - Strengthening the Spiritual Life. New York: Harper, 1951. (Box 27)
    - The Christian Understanding of God. New York: Harper, 1951. (Box 27)
    - The Sun and the Umbrella. New York: Harper, 1953. (Box 28)
    - Christian Faith and Higher Education. New York: Harper, 1954. (Box 28)
    - Making Religion Real. New York: Harper, 1955. (Box 28)
    - Fortalecimiento de la Vida Espiritual. Buenos Aires: P.F. La Aurora, 1957. (Box 28)
    - Christ and the Christian. New York: Harper, 1958. (Box 28)
    - Know Your Faith. New York: Harper and Row, 1959. (Box 28)
    - Searchlights on Contemporary Theology. New York: Harper, 1961. (Box 28)
    - God's New Age: A Book of Sermons. New York: Harper, 1962. (Box 29)
    - A Theology for Christian Prayer. Nashville: Tidings, 1963. (Box 29)
    - Reason in Religion. London: Nelson, 1963. (Box 29)
    - The Finality of Faith. New York: Harper and Row, 1963. (Box 29)
    - PILLARS OF FAITH (JAPANESE TRANSLATION). Tokyo: Shinkyo Shuppansha Pub. Co., 1964. (Box 29)
    - The Living God of Nowhere and Nothing. Philadelphia: Westminster, 1966. (Box 29)
    - Swedish Contributions to Modern Theology. New York: Harper Torchbooks, 1967. (Box 29)
    - "Social Motifs in Christianity, Fascism, Marxism and Freudianism." In Week of Work Pamphlet, 24. s.l.: National Council on Religion in Higher Education, 1939. (Box 30)
    - "Personal Aspects of Sin and Its Forgiveness." [publication unknown] (May 1941): 15-24. (Box 30)
    - "Purpose and Progress: A Christian Doctrine of History." Christendom 6 (Winter 1941): 44-55. (Box 30)
    - "The Second Conference on Science, Philosohpy and Religion: Religious Background of Democratic Ideas." Information Service 20/36 (Saturday, November 8, 1941): 8. (Box 30)
    - "A Theological Doctrine of Man." Religion in Life 11 (Fall 1942): (Box 30)
    - "Faith and Reason." Christendom 8/2 (Spring 1943): 217-230. (Box 30)
    - "O Death, Where is Thy Sting?" Motive 4 (Nov. 1943): 17-18. (Box 30)
    - "Which Way Christus Victor?" Christus Victor (Jan. 1943): 2-3. (Box 30)
    - "A Definition of Christian Liberalism." The Watchman-Examiner (May 11, 1944): 456. (Box 30)
    - Commission of the Federal Council of the Churches in Christ in America, The Relation of the Church to the War in Light of the Christian Faith. New York: The Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America, 1944. (Box 30)
    - "The Christian Faith, the Church, and War." Fellowship 11/2 (Feb. 1945): 20-22. (Box 30)
    - "A Fellowship of Free Men." Missionary Herald 142 (Jan. 1946): 3. (Box 30)
    - "Jesus as Lord." Intercollegian (Dec. 1946): 5-6. (Box 30)
    - "The Savior Still." Review and Expositor 44 (July 1947): 185-300. (Box 30)
    - "The Holy Spirit and the Individual." The Asbury Seminarian 3 (Fall 1948): 96-102. (Box 30)
    - "Church Union and Hard Hearts." Christian Century 67 (Feb. 15, 1950): 207-208. (Box 30)
    - "An Abounding New Year." British Weekly 131/3399 (Jan. 3, 1952). 1. (Box 30)
    - "Eskatologi och etik." Tro Och Liv 5 (1952): 196-207. (Box 30)
    - "Family Worship for Christmas." The Upper Room Pulpit 19/5 (Dec. 1953): 58. (Box 30)
    - "Las Devociones Familares como medio para fortalecer la Vida Espiritual." Educacion Christiana 32 (Apr.-June 1953): 10-13, 37. (Box 30)
    - Meeting God Through the Bible. Nashville: Upper Room, 1954. (Box 30)
    - "Where Do We Go From Here in Theology?" The Chaplain 12/5 (Oct. 1955): 1-8. (Box 30)
    - "Prayer is Power." In A Guide to Small Group Worship, 1-5. Newton Centre, MA: Religious Life Committee at Andover Newton Theological School, 1960. (Box 30)